If you could say a prediction for something like SageMaker in the next year or two,
在未来一两年内
where do you think some of your energy's will go?
你认为 SageMaker 将朝着什么方向发展？
Will it be more data security or other kinds
未来更侧重于数据安全性吗？
of features do you think you'll see more of in future?
还是侧重于其他功能？
Yeah. That's a very good question.
嗯问得好
So to get back to how we build.
回到 SageMaker 的构建方式上
So we do have two ways of looking at it.
可以分为两个方面
One is that we know a thing or two by working with a lot of customers,
一方面 我们与很多客户合作
and then we hear a lot of needs.
聆听他们的需求
For example, needs four more automation,
例如自动化需求
needs for more integration.
集成需求
If you think about operationalizing an end-to-end machine learning workflow,
对于端到端机器学习工作流程
now you can have tools for building,
现在有各种工具 包括构建工具
you can have tools for training,
训练工具
you can have tools for deploying.
以及部署工具
But if you have to do that every day,
但是如果每天都是这些工作
then you probably want to have tools for lifecycle management, integration,
那么你肯定希望有各种其他工具 包括生命周期管理
experiment management, workflows, and all these other things
集成 实验管理 工作流程工具等等
that really automate the whole thing.
使整个流程变得自动化
So towards the end of last year,
在去年底
we announced a lot of peripheral features around SageMaker.
我们围绕 SageMaker 推出了很多外围功能
Features for serverless integration, for example.
例如无服务器集成
Features for GitHub integration to enable collaboration.
便于协作的 GitHub 集成
Features for experiment management to be able to
实验管理功能
compare the results that you have from two different machine learning models,
便于比较两个不同机器学习模型的结果
and then look at them side-by-side and see which ones satisfy your metrics.
然后并排查看两个模型 看看哪个模型满足你的指标需求
So we are heavily investing into really connecting the dots in an end-to-end lifecycle.
我们投入大量精力 致力于将端到端生命周期的每个环节连接到一起
This is other thing that is happening where once you have a machine learning model,
另一方面 有了机器学习模型后
there's really three ways you can employ the model.
可以通过三种方式部署模型
One is that you can have that behind
一个是实时网络应用端点
a real time endpoint web application that can serve real traffic.
能够实时提供服务
The second thing is that you can use that for batch processing.
第二个是批量处理
For example, you want to crunch the sales of the last month or year,
例如 你希望查看过去一个月或一年的销量
and then you can pass the data through batch scoring exercise.
可以将数据传入批量评分系统
The third one that is becoming more and more popular nowadays is that you really
第三种方式如今变得越来越热门
want to get a machine learning models closest to the users as possible.
我们需要让机器学习模型尽量接近用户
So, for example, you want to be able to put a machine learning model in the device
例如 将机器学习模型部署到设备上
like the Echo device closer to the user,
例如 Echo 设备
or in a mobile application,
移动应用
or in an IoT device,
物联网设备
or predictive agriculture, or something like that,
预测农业
or in an Internet disconnected area.
或没有互联网的区域
So you can put the machine learning model and a small tool that you can use
可以将机器学习模型放在很小的工具中
to look at a crop and then see if that crop
在没有互联网连接的区域
is healthy in an area that is not connected to the Internet.
查看农作物是否健康
Then these ecosystems come with their own challenges because you have
这些生态系统本身就有挑战性
to get the model to be tiny enough to fit into those little devices.
因为模型必须很小 才能放到很小的设备上
So we put a lot of energy around that to make sure that
我们投入大量精力
after you train a machine learning model on the Cloud with a lot of GPUs,
使你在通过云端平台使用大量 GPU 训练机器学习模型后
you can compile that,
能够编译模型
get it smaller, but maintain the same amount of accuracy that you can maintain,
使模型更小 但是保持同等的准确率 而性能更高
and increase the performance because the model is a lot smaller but high performance.
模型小多了 但是性能很高
Then put that in those devices and really bring
然后将模型放到设备上
machine learning models closest to the users in a data as possible.
尽量方便用户使用这些机器学习模型
So you should expect us to put
我们将围绕
more energy around these kinds of challenges that we're seeing in a field,
业内面临的挑战投入越来越多的精力
like where do machine learning models reading it to be,
例如机器学习模型到底该朝着什么方向发展
and find ways to build technology around that.
并找到围绕这些方向开发技术的方式
What is the lifecycle of automating machine learning models and
什么是自动化机器学习工具的生命周期？
operationalizing that and in building technology to connect these dots.
使这一生命周期变得程序化 开发连接各个环节的技术
Of course, like I say,
当然 就像我说的
90 to 95 percent of the time we just talked to customers and trying
90-95% 的时候我们都与客户沟通
to find out what they want and we built that.
了解他们希望我们构建什么样的工具
So, yes, we're building according to what we know,
没错 我们根据所了解的情况构建工具
but we're also building according to the needs that are there, existing out there.
但是也根据已有的需求构建工具
I'm curious to know a bit more about your background.
我很好奇你是什么样的背景？
How did you become interested in machine learning and make your way to Amazon?
为何对机器学习感兴趣 并进入 Amazon 工作？
Sure. I did study physics and computer science,
嗯我的专业是物理学和计算机科学
so that's my background.
这就是我的教育背景
I did work as a deployment engineer in the past,
我之前是一名部署工程师
and I did work as an on-site engineer in payment systems,
并且在银行当过外派工程师
and eventually into big data and Hadoop type of technologies.
最终进入大数据和 Hadoop 技术领域
So I've always been around science, and engineering,
我一直都对科学 工程
and building systems, and deploying systems,
构建系统和部署系统
and trying to integrate them at scale.
并大规模地集成系统感兴趣
So when I got into Amazon about five-and-a-half years ago,
我在大概五年半前进入了 Amazon
I got in as a Hadoop Engineering Manager,
应聘的是 Hadoop 工程经理
where I built a team of Hadoop and big data engineers.
我组建了 Hadoop 和大数据工程师团队
What we were doing there back then really was to play with the Hadoop tools,
我们当时就是研究各种 Hadoop 工具
Spark, when it came out and the other tools in the ecosystem.
例如当时刚推出的 Spark 以及该生态系统的其他工具
Essentially, it was a time when big data was growing big as a field.
当时大数据很火热 发展成了一个专门的领域
It was still [inaudible] it but it was growing a little bit.
如今依然很热门 但是当时的发展势头最强劲
The small analogy that I draw with the times today is,
如今机器学习的火热发展
machine learning is today a little bit what big data was five or six years ago,
就和五六年前的大数据一样
where a lot of people who are getting into the field,
当时有很多人都投身到这个领域
but the technology wasn't really there yet to help people adopt big data.
但是缺少帮助人们采用大数据的工具
It's playing catch up.
是一种跟风追赶
Yeah. It's playing catch up.
是的是一种跟风追赶
So it was very useful from our perspective, from my perspective,
从我的角度来看
to observe the investments that
我很关注 AWS
AWS put into building Amazon Elastic MapReduce, for example,
对 Amazon Elastic MapReduce 的投资
that made Hadoop accessible,
使 Hadoop 便于大家使用
and then the other tools on top of the Hadoop ecosystem and make that accessible.
然后在 Hadoop 生态系统的基础之上推出其他工具
So I spent some time in that ecosystem,
我在这个生态系统待了一段时间
and then when we started investing into building machine learning platforms,
之后 当我们开始构建机器学习平台时
it was basically a repeat of what we've done with big data,
基本上与大数据的模式一样
and that's how I got into machine learning.
因此我进入了机器学习领域
But to get myself ready before actually doing machine learning full-time,
但是在成为机器学习全职员工之前
I was taking courses online.
我参加了一些在线课程
I took the Coursera course by the famous Andrew Ing, what?
我在六七年前 大概是 2012 2011 年
Six, seven years ago now, 2012, 2011.
参加了著名的 Andrew Ng 的 Coursera 课程
So there's this continuous and perpetual learning aspect
我一直都在不断学习
that has always been part of my process where I want to learn new languages,
不断掌握新的语言
I want to learn new tools,
我希望学习新的工具
I want to learn new technology,
学习新的技术
and machine learning was naturally fitting in that mindset.
很自然地就接触了机器学习
That's really how I got into it.
我就是这么进入机器学习领域的